A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Human Rights and Governance Program, Program Director, Office Files of Shepard Forman FA717
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Human Rights and Governance Program, Program Director, Office Files of Shepard Forman
1980-1991
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA717
19.2 Cubic Feet
Conditions Governing Access
Material is open for scholarly research, with prior archival review.
Material more than ten years old is open for scholarly research.
Select individual files are restricted, as noted. Permission to access these files must be obtained from the Ford Foundation before scholarly access is permitted.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be restricted from scholarly research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment.
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be restricted from scholarly research at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/RAC Head of Reference.
Separated Materials
Reports by staff and consultants were transferred to their respective collections in the Archives. Transfers are noted on cross-reference sheets in Forman's records. An appendix to this register lists the reports that were transferred.
Scope and Contents
Shepard Forman served as the Program Officer-in-Charge of the Human Rights & Governance Program from 1981 to 1986. In 1987, the title of Program Officer-in-Charge was changed to Director and Forman served in that title until 1990. He became Director of the International Affairs Program in 1991 and retired from the Ford Foundation in 1995.
This collection documents Forman's activities as Program Director of the Human Rights and Governance Program. During his tenure, the Human Rights and Governance Program encompassed two of six major areas of funding – Human Rights and Social Justice and Governance and Public Policy. This Program supported the promotion and protection of fundamental civil and political liberties worldwide and provided support for analysis of governmental structures and policies in developed countries and in Third World countries. The records of the Program Director are significant because they document the development of new program ideas with input from the President and Board of Trustees. These papers also document work by the Program staff in developing new initiatives and implementing grant activity in the areas of human rights and public policy on a national and international scope. Activities documented in the files include creation of program initiatives, preparation of financial materials, reports, and strategy papers that were presented to the Board of Trustees and documentation of task forces and study group activities. Of interest are the background files on the development of an AIDS funding program that involved other private foundations.
Arrangement
The collection is composed of 16 boxes and is comprised of the following series:
I. Background Files, 1980-1991 II. AIDS Background Files, 1987-1988 III. General Correspondence Files, 1981-1982 IV. General Files, 1985-1992 V. Trip Files, 1981-1990
Ford Foundation
- Background Files, 1980-1991; I
  Scope and Contents
  Series I, Background Files, 1980-1991, includes grant recommendations, proposals, reports, publications, notes, and meeting materials (i.e. agendas, notes). Some of these files are related to grantees and potential grantees. Other materials served as reference files providing background information on particular organizations or topics. Also included are financial projections, discussion papers, program reviews, and program statements.
  - Population Grants (Box 1 (SK #34648), Folder 1)
  - President's Report to Board of Trustees (Draft Outline) (Box 1 (SK #34648), Folder 2)
  - Program planning, 1982 (Box 1 (SK #34648), Folder 3)
  - Committee on Public Policy & Social Organizations (Box 1 (SK #34648), Folder 4)
  - Puerto Rico Legal Project (Box 1 (SK #34648), Folder 5)
  - Jeff Puryear Paper, 1979 (Box 1 (SK #34648), Folder 6)
  - Center on International Policy (Box 1 (SK #34648), Folder 7)
  - Rhona Rapoport (Box 1 (SK #34648), Folder 8)
  - Religious Freedom (Box 1 (SK #34648), Folder 9)
  - Rural America (Box 1 (SK #34648), Folder 10)
  - PRI (Box 1 (SK #34648), Folder 11)
  - Sin Censura (Box 1 (SK #34648), Folder 12)
  - Whitten Norman (Box 1 (SK #34648), Folder 13)
  - Sacha Runa Research Foundation (Box 1 (SK #34648), Folder 14)
  - A. Sakharov Conference, 1981 May 1 - 2 (Box 1 (SK #34648), Folder 15)
  - N.Y. Council of Law Associates, Barbara Schatz (Box 1 (SK #34648), Folder 16)
  - Martin Scurrah (Lima, Peru office) (Box 1 (SK #34648), Folder 17)
  - CELS (Center for Legal and Social Studies, Argentina) (Box 1 (SK #34648), Folder 18)
  - Expense orders for books and station (Box 1 (SK #34648), Folder 19)
  - Title VI Legislation (Box 1 (SK #34648), Folder 20)
  - Interim Reports of Theme Teams (Box 1 (SK #34648), Folder 21)
  - TOLA (Box 1 (SK #34648), Folder 22)
  - "U.N. University's Next Stage" Rector Soedjatmoko (Box 1 (SK #34648), Folder 23)
  - WOLA (Washington Office on Latin America) (Box 1 (SK #34648), Folder 24)
  - Trip to Washington - April - May 1981, International Teaching Rights (Box 1 (SK #34648), Folder 25)
  - Wilson Center (Box 1 (SK #34648), Folder 26)
  - Women's Position – Rio (Box 1 (SK #34648), Folder 27)
  - Women's Program Group (Box 1 (SK #34648), Folder 28)
  - Women (Box 1 (SK #34648), Folder 29)
  - International Women's Resource Agency, Inc. (Box 1 (SK #34648), Folder 30)
  - Women's Rights, India (Box 1 (SK #34648), Folder 31)
  - Women, A-Z (Box 1 (SK #34648), Folder 32)
  - Women's Studies (Box 1 (SK #34648), Folder 33)
  - Zalaquette, Jose, 1981 February 26 (Box 1 (SK #34648), Folder 34)
  - Native Americans – Consultancy (Box 2 (SK #36049), Folder 1)
  - Africa (Box 2 (SK #36049), Folder 2)
  - Amnesty International (Box 2 (SK #36049), Folder 3)
  - Amuesha – Yanachaga Project – Peru (Box 2 (SK #36049), Folder 4)
  - Anthropology Resource Center (Box 2 (SK #36049), Folder 5)
  - Anti-Slavery Society (Box 2 (SK #36049), Folder 6)
  - FY1982 Program appropriations (Box 2 (SK #36049), Folder 7)
  - Aspen Institute (Box 2 (SK #36049), Folder 8)
  - Boston Trip (Box 2 (SK #36049), Folder 9)
  - 1982-83 Budgets. Originals and extra copies (Box 2 (SK #36049), Folder 10)
  - East Timor (Box 2 (SK #36049), Folder 11)
  - T. Kessinger (Box 2 (SK #36049), Folder 12)
  - Program activities – Hungary (Box 2 (SK #36049), Folder 13)
  - Ethnic Conflict (Box 2 (SK #36049), Folder 14)
  - SF - Trip to California (Box 2 (SK #36049), Folder 15)
  - Patricia Campe – Aguilar Film Project 10/17/80, Brasil [sic], 1980 (Box 2 (SK #36049), Folder 16)
  - Community Level Action programs (Box 2 (SK #36049), Folder 17)
  - CODEJU Commission Nacional Pro Dereshos Javeniles (Box 2 (SK #36049), Folder 18)
  - Child Development and Child Care in Latin America (Box 2 (SK #36049), Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, A-Z, 1981 July (Box 2 (SK #36049), Folder 20)
  - ECLA/UNDP meeting (Box 2 (SK #36049), Folder 21)
  - Rural Studies, Latin America (Box 2 (SK #36049), Folder 22)
  - Ethical Culture Schools (Box 2 (SK #36049), Folder 23)
  - Organized Crime (Box 2 (SK #36049), Folder 24)
  - Don Travel (Box 2 (SK #36049), Folder 25)
  - Patricia W. Fagen (Box 2 (SK #36049), Folder 26)
  - Frank Richard W. (Box 2 (SK #36049), Folder 27)
  - Forward Planning (Box 2 (SK #36049), Folder 28)
  - Friedman Conference (Box 2 (SK #36049), Folder 29)
  - Helsinki Watch Committee (Box 2 (SK #36049), Folder 30)
  - Human Rights – Eastern Europe (Box 2 (SK #36049), Folder 31)
  - Human Rights - The Media (Box 2 (SK #36049), Folder 32)
  - Human Rights - Other Funders (Box 2 (SK #36049), Folder 33)
  - "Fact-finding by International Nongovernmental Organizations for the Implementation of Human Rights" by David Weissbrodt and James McCarthy (Box 2 (SK #36049), Folder 34)
  - Human Rights Research (Box 2 (SK #36049), Folder 35)
  - Indian Rights/ICSA Conference (Box 2 (SK #36049), Folder 36)
  - International Human Rights Internship Program (Box 2 (SK #36049), Folder 37)
  - Inter-American Institute of Human Rights (Box 2 (SK #36049), Folder 38)
  - Center for Inter-American Relations - Central America Series (P.D. Bell) 5:30pm (Tuesday, March 24th) (Box 2 (SK #36049), Folder 39)
  - International Commission of Jurists (Box 2 (SK #36049), Folder 40)
  - International League for Human Rights (grant) (Box 2 (SK #36049), Folder 41)
  - SF: FF Interoffice Memos, A-Z, 1981 January - March (Box 2 (SK #36049), Folder 42)
  - Americas Watch (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 1)
  - FY1981 Program Appropriations (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 2)
  - Ford Foundation Status Report - regular appropriations (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 3)
  - Special appropriations for women's programs (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 4)
  - Weekly "Reports of "Approved Actions" (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 5)
  - Commission on U. S. – Brazilian Relations (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 6)
  - Aspen Institute Dinner, March, 1981. HR: The treatment of journalists, 1981 March (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 7)
  - Budget tables for program planning (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 8)
  - Quarterly Budget Projections (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 9)
  - Lawyers' Committee for Civil Rights under Law (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 10)
  - Colombian Folklore Institute (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 11)
  - Grant recommendation and grant proposal - Latin America (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 12)
  - China (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 13)
  - Dahrendorf, Ralf (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 14)
  - Decter, Midge (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 15)
  - Dressner, Howard (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 16)
  - El Salvador and the Press (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 17)
  - Conference: Structural Approaches to ethnic conflict (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 18)
  - Ethnic conflict workshops (W. Goldman) (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 19)
  - FF field reports. Information copies (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 20)
  - Hispanics (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 21)
  - Human Rights - State Dept. (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 22)
  - Human Rights - Latin America (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 23)
  - Latin America Human Rights - Clippings (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 24)
  - Human Rights - Inter-American Congress of Philosophy (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 25)
  - Human Rights (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 26)
  - Human Rights - Central America (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 27)
  - Council on Foundations (32nd Annual conference) (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 28)
  - Confidentiality of Foundation grant files - reporting (gov't officials) (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 29)
  - Human Rights - Latin America and the Caribbean (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 30)
  - 10th Inter-American Congress of Philosophy (Gruender, David) (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 31)
  - Aid Human Rights (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 32)
  - Human Rights grants - all foundations (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 33)
  - Human Rights and Intellectual Freedom. March 1981 study - confidential, 1981 March (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 34)
  - Human Rights and Intellectual Freedom. Information paper, 1975 November (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 35)
  - SF: Human Rights and Justice. Introduction and problems, 1981 Spring (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 36)
  - Human Rights Program draft (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 37)
  - Human Rights and Justice Working Group (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 38)
  - Human Rights: Needs and priorities (Rosalyn Higgins), 1973 September (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 39)
  - Human Rights Internet - Laurie Weisberg (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 40)
  - Latin American Human rights Initiative (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 41)
  - Lawyers' Committee for Human Rights (Mike Posner) (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 42)
  - U. Ottowa. H.R. Institute. Walter Tarnosky (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 43)
  - Citizen's Committee for Immigration (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 44)
  - Indian Rights Files (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 45)
  - Indian Rights Files (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 46)
  - Indian Rights/OLAC (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 47)
  - Legal Aid Programs - Asia (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 48)
  - United Nations Research Institute for Social Development - Participation program (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 49)
  - Immigration Policy Research (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 50)
  - National Forum on Immigration and Refugee Policy (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 51)
  - Frank Jones (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 52)
  - Kiss, Alexander, March 31, 1981 - International Institute of Human Rights, 1981 March 31 (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 53)
  - Worker's Culture (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 54)
  - LIWASA Standing Committee on Human Rights (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 55)
  - Latin American Culture (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 56)
  - Fund for Michigan (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 57)
  - Congresswoman Barbara Mikulski (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 58)
  - Migrant Educational Data International Record (MEDIR) (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 59)
  - Municipal government - East Ralo Alto (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 60)
  - National Council of La Raza (NCLR) - RGA (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 61)
  - National Urban League - RGA (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 62)
  - OLAC Budget (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 63)
  - OLAC Reorganization (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 64)
  - OLAC staff patterns (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 65)
  - OLAC travel and vacation schedules (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 66)
  - Officers' meeting (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 67)
  - Pending: Anthropology Resource Center (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 68)
  - Pending: Brazil office (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 69)
  - Pending: Colombia office (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 70)
  - Pending: Public Policy Commission (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 71)
  - Poland – Working File (Box 3 (SK #34630), Folder 72)
  - IPSA (Box 4 (SK #34804), Folder 1)
  - International Affairs (Box 4 (SK #34804), Folder 2)
  - Human Rights (Box 4 (SK #34804), Folder 3)
  - Immigrants and Refugees FF working group (Box 4 (SK #34804), Folder 4)
  - Indian Rights (Box 4 (SK #34804), Folder 5)
  - Leo Kuper - Draft RGA 7/81 Genocide. Study of International Protection, 1981 July (Box 4 (SK #34804), Folder 6)
  - International Red Cross (Box 4 (SK #34804), Folder 7)
  - Job Files (Box 4 (SK #34804), Folder 8)
  - Joint Center for Political Studies. Eddie Williams (Box 4 (SK #34804), Folder 9)
  - Latin America (Box 4 (SK #34804), Folder 10)
  - Latin America: Trip report of Dorothy Marshall and Harriet Robb (FF trustees) (Box 4 (SK #34804), Folder 11)
  - Legal Service Backup Center (Box 4 (SK #34804), Folder 12)
  - MALDEF (Mexican American Legal Defense Fund) (Box 4 (SK #34804), Folder 13)
  - University of Minnesota (Box 4 (SK #34804), Folder 14)
  - Herman Montealegre (Inst. Interameric Derechos Humanos) (Box 4 (SK #34804), Folder 15)
  - National Youth Employment Coalition (Box 4 (SK #34804), Folder 16)
  - Norman Foundation (Box 4 (SK #34804), Folder 17)
  - Notre Dame - Father Hesbrough (Box 4 (SK #34804), Folder 18)
  - Pan American Seminar on Peace (Box 4 (SK #34804), Folder 19)
  - SF personal files: Claims for damages (Box 4 (SK #34804), Folder 20)
  - SF personal files: Personal filing (Box 4 (SK #34804), Folder 21)
  - Pending calls (recruitment files - Asst. Prog. Officer) (Box 4 (SK #34804), Folder 22)
  - Proposed actions reviewed at Program Officers' meeting (Box 4 (SK #34804), Folder 23)
  - Trustees' discussions on Education and Culture (Box 4 (SK #34804), Folder 24)
  - Public Policy – Women (Box 4 (SK #34804), Folder 25)
  - RAND Corporation Institute for Civil Justice (Box 4 (SK #34804), Folder 26)
  - Repatriation (Box 4 (SK #34804), Folder 27)
  - SSRC (Social Science Research Center) (Box 4 (SK #34804), Folder 28)
  - Barry Stein Consultancy (Box 4 (SK #34804), Folder 29)
  - Robert J. Stein (Box 4 (SK #34804), Folder 30)
  - Survival International (Box 4 (SK #34804), Folder 31)
  - Jacob Timerman (Box 4 (SK #34804), Folder 32)
  - Travel Center Week 11/5-10, Washington, DC (Box 4 (SK #34804), Folder 33)
  - Urban Morgan Institute (Box 4 (SK #34804), Folder 34)
  - Women & Economics Conference (Dwyer, Daisy) (Box 4 (SK #34804), Folder 35)
  - Women's Program Group (Box 4 (SK #34804), Folder 36)
  - Writers & Scholars - RGA (Box 4 (SK #34804), Folder 37)
  - Affirmative Action (Box 4 (SK #34804), Folder 38)
  - Affirmative Action Data (Box 4 (SK #34804), Folder 39)
  - Agrarian Rights (Box 4 (SK #34804), Folder 40)
  - Agricultural Programs (Box 4 (SK #34804), Folder 41)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science (AAAS) (Box 4 (SK #34804), Folder 42)
  - Anthropology meetings 1981 (Barbara Miller) (Box 4 (SK #34804), Folder 43)
  - Society for Anthropological Economics meeting, 1981 April 26 - 29 (Box 4 (SK #34804), Folder 44)
  - Association for Political and Legal Anthropology (Box 4 (SK #34804), Folder 45)
  - Brazil – General (Box 4 (SK #34804), Folder 46)
  - December 1981 Board of Trustees meeting, 1981 December (Box 4 (SK #34804), Folder 47)
  - Agriculture and Natural Resources (Box 5 (SK #38393), Folder 1)
  - A.I.D. – Washington Agency for International Development/Democratization (Box 5 (SK #38393), Folder 1A)
  - Anti-slavery Society (Box 5 (SK #38393), Folder 2)
  - Argentine Group of Forensic Anthropologists (Box 5 (SK #38393), Folder 3)
  - Maureen Berman Report – Special Meeting on Journalists and Extra-legal Executions (Box 5 (SK #38393), Folder 4)
  - Brookings - April 6-7, 1987, 1987 April 6 - 7 (Box 5 (SK #38393), Folder 5)
  - Brookings - B. K. MacLaury (Box 5 (SK #38393), Folder 6)
  - Brookings - Litan (Box 5 (SK #38393), Folder 7)
  - Brookings - 10/26/90 (H. Aaron/S. Riegel), 1990 October 26 (Box 5 (SK #38393), Folder 8)
  - Common Good - Isabel Sawhill – U.I. Social Welfare Summary (Box 5 (SK #38393), Folder 9)
  - Common Good - Senate Commission – "Common Good", 1991 March 4 (Box 5 (SK #38393), Folder 10)
  - Common Good - General (Box 5 (SK #38393), Folder 11)
  - Common Good - AEI (Box 5 (SK #38393), Folder 12)
  - Common Good - Committee for Economic Development (Box 5 (SK #38393), Folder 13)
  - Common Good - National Academy for Social Insurance, 1990 May 17 (Box 5 (SK #38393), Folder 14)
  - Common Good - National Academy for Social Insurance – "Common Good," Wash. D.C., 1989 November 1 (Box 5 (SK #38393), Folder 15)
  - Common Good - American Assembly, 1989 September 25 (Box 5 (SK #38393), Folder 16)
  - Common Good - Robert Finch (Common Good – ACLS) (Box 5 (SK #38393), Folder 17)
  - Common Good - American Assembly – LBJ School of Public Affairs (Box 5 (SK #38393), Folder 18)
  - Common Good - American Assembly, Sacramento, CA, 1990 November 15 - 18 (Box 5 (SK #38393), Folder 19)
  - Consultatial Group on Biological Diversity (Box 5 (SK #38393), Folder 20)
  - William Duggan – West Africa Media Program (Box 5 (SK #38393), Folder 21)
  - Wilma Espinoza, Consultant – National Hispanic Women's Organizations (Box 5 (SK #38393), Folder 22)
  - German Marshall Fund (Box 5 (SK #38393), Folder 23)
  - Crawford Goodwin/M. Nacht – "The Forgotten Payoff" (Box 5 (SK #38393), Folder 24)
  - Grantmaking in East/Central Europe (SEEG) (Box 5 (SK #38393), Folder 25)
  - Grameen Bank (Box 5 (SK #38393), Folder 26)
  - Gridley Hall Paper – Legal Services in Developing Countries (Box 5 (SK #38393), Folder 27)
  - The Ford Foundation Hispanic Leadership Development Conference (Box 5 (SK #38393), Folder 28)
  - Reports on the Hispanic Leadership Opportunity Program (Box 5 (SK #38393), Folder 29)
  - Hispanic Policy and Research Funders Meeting (Box 5 (SK #38393), Folder 30)
  - Hispanic Task Force, 1985 January 16 (Box 5 (SK #38393), Folder 31)
  - Hispanic Leadership Opportunity Program (HLOP) (Box 5 (SK #38393), Folder 32)
  - Indigenous People (Box 5 (SK #38393), Folder 33)
  - Institute for Human Sciences – Vienna (Box 5 (SK #38393), Folder 34)
  - Lardent/McCalpin Report Fellowships and Senior Lawyers (Box 5 (SK #38393), Folder 35)
  - Institute for European-Latin America Relations (Box 5 (SK #38393), Folder 36)
  - International Center for Development Policy (Box 5 (SK #38393), Folder 37)
  - Bill Butler – ICJ, 1989 October 3 (Box 5 (SK #38393), Folder 38)
  - International Federation for Survival and Development of Humanity (Box 5 (SK #38393), Folder 39)
  - Andrei Kozyrev (Box 5 (SK #38393), Folder 40)
  - Alexander Lavar (Box 5 (SK #38393), Folder 41)
  - Center for Democratic Renewal (Dan Levitas) (Box 5 (SK #38393), Folder 42)
  - Institutions, Groups, Individuals in Moscow (HR & G) (Box 5 (SK #38393), Folder 43)
  - Multilateral Challenges (Box 5 (SK #38393), Folder 44)
  - Crawfurd Goodwin and Micheal Nacht Report – International Educational Exchange (Box 5 (SK #38393), Folder 45)
  - The Nation Article (Box 5 (SK #38393), Folder 46)
  - National Security Archives (Box 5 (SK #38393), Folder 47)
  - Nun, Jose (Box 5 (SK #38393), Folder 48)
  - Reichmann, Rebecca (Strategy Paper on Civil Rights and Economic Opportunities for Blacks and Women in Brazil) (Box 6 (SK #38674), Folder 1)
  - Rapoport, Rhona (Advancement of Blacks and Women in South Africa) (Box 6 (SK #38674), Folder 2)
  - Abueva, J. (U. of Philippines) (Box 6 (SK #38674), Folder 3)
  - Philippor, Igor (Box 6 (SK #38674), Folder 4)
  - Poverty & Natural Resources (Kamla Chowdhry, India) (Box 6 (SK #38674), Folder 5)
  - Proxy Committee (Box 6 (SK #38674), Folder 6)
  - Przeworski, Adam (includes c.v.) (Box 6 (SK #38674), Folder 7)
  - Research Advisory Committee, Belmont, MD (Box 6 (SK #38674), Folder 8)
  - Role of US Foundations in East/Central Europe (Box 6 (SK #38674), Folder 9)
  - South Africa Briefing, 1989 January 1 (Box 6 (SK #38674), Folder 10)
  - Salett, Stan. Presidential Transitions – Wash, D.C., 1988 February 3 (Box 6 (SK #38674), Folder 11)
  - Salett, Elizabeth (International Counseling Center) (Box 6 (SK #38674), Folder 12)
  - USSR (General SEESG) (Box 6 (SK #38674), Folder 13)
  - SEEG (Meeting notes) (Box 6 (SK #38674), Folder 14)
  - SEESG (USSR Grants, equipment and supplies) (Box 6 (SK #38674), Folder 15)
  - Project recommendations for USSR (Box 6 (SK #38674), Folder 16)
  - SF – USSR Trip Report (Box 6 (SK #38674), Folder 17)
  - Picken, Margo (USSR Trip report) (Box 6 (SK #38674), Folder 18)
  - Survival Foundation (USSR) 2/5/91 (E. Velikor), 1991 February 5 (Box 6 (SK #38674), Folder 19)
  - U.N.D.P. (Confidential) (Box 6 (SK #38674), Folder 20)
  - UN Leadership for the Future, 1991 August 14 (Box 6 (SK #38674), Folder 21)
  - Vetere, Eduardo (Meeting with Margo Picken – 5/19/89), 1989 May 19 (Box 6 (SK #38674), Folder 22)
  - Evaluation of the Voter Education Project (Box 6 (SK #38674), Folder 23)
  - Williams, Shirley (JFK School) Project Liberty (Box 6 (SK #38674), Folder 24)
  - International Women’s Rights Organizations, 1991 February 15 (Box 6 (SK #38674), Folder 25)
  - Scott, Jim (Yale) (Box 6 (SK #38674), Folder 26)
  - Presentation to Trustees (Rationale for new Human Rights and Governance Program) (Box 6 (SK #38674), Folder 27)
  - HR&G Program files (Box 6 (SK #38674), Folder 28)
  - Concept paper (SF comments on Harry Dodds' concept paper) (Box 6 (SK #38674), Folder 29)
  - Bell, Peter (Graduate Training Programs in Public Policy supported by the Ford Foundation) (Box 6 (SK #38674), Folder 30)
  - Review of Public Policy and Social Organization Program (Box 6 (SK #38674), Folder 31)
  - National Affairs Review (Session 5: Law and Justice Program) (Box 6 (SK #38674), Folder 32)
  - Philippines - Meeting in Philippines (Box 7 (SK #38867), Folder 1)